I'm gonna go on to the laundry room
let's do about 10 15 minutes and then
we'll take a break okay
number luck Johnny locating some time to
ponder checkout sorry
gangee pants soon Mottola soon unit lost
some juice ago soon okay we finished the
six main types types of closure
Stan Lee finished the other ones and
very nicely I like how they grouped them
whose I deal with that is that any
Chinese commentary how they group them
together like you group this you made
subgroups like all the way you made that
Wow okay alright so he taught it from
the AH be dumber and now we're gonna
come back now the second part is how do
you get a mental affliction how does one
start in your mind okay got it all right
hmm hundred dollars give me a good
example to answer this question huh
catch it's too easy I wouldn't give a
hundred dollars for a kitchen now I got
interested before he wasn't interested
the second part of a bunker repurchase
presentation of clay sure is how do they
start up what triggers them and I wanted
for $30 because I'm so irritated that
you didn't get it what's a nice example
to talk about how they start how do you
start to get nervous about next week $20
huh
yeah come on
I want a metaphor
huh two dollars metaphor $1 you owe me
$100 the nose and the face okay then
nose in the face it's been a long time
since we talked about it we talked about
it this morning yeah I mean the
punchline of this section the conclusion
of this section has to be you need the
body you need the face to have the nose
okay which means yeah you must
misunderstand your husband or you cannot
get upset and you must miss understand
your work at home waiting for you or you
wouldn't get nervous today but you will
get nervous today and so will i I'm
already nervous and it means there must
be a face there somewhere there must be
some misunderstanding going on
underneath okay so take it home take the
take this lar mem home work on it okay
in theory you could be having a retreat
next week - okay
at work if you really understand okay
all right here we go yo moma GTECH
airram bunny what are the stages in
which a negative emotion grows Tanya
talks on your mantra chicken dong ding
dong ding dong ditcher all o negative
emotions especially the big six always
come from believing that something is
coming from its own side okay must and
especially the version of they're called
dicta what's that mean misunderstand me
and mine and not denying jimbe dicta
okay which is the link of come on word
wake up his first link okay the first
naked wheeler you cannot have suffering
without misunderstanding yourself okay
all right Jake Taylor Jungmann Daniel
Dan lenient on Jake it's audited a
mariachi to shape a tunnel so if we
accept those thinkers who say that
misunderstanding which creates your pain
and misunderstanding which
misunderstands me are the same we had it
above anybody remember somebody said
they're the same thing okay
I think it was Charlie Quixote you can
check okay I think it was chanting candy
yeah okay and then a song I had the
opposite idea okay
Kjetil archenemy che bella lamour open
it all and if you're in the other system
which doesn't say that the main
misunderstanding is yourself which now
we go to a Sangha okay and there was
somebody else was it just this angle of
us abandoned yeah cuchini okay
mari bonito or anyway misunderstanding
next week is why you feel nervous about
next week okay if you understood next
week you wouldn't feel nervous about it
okay in the same way that if you
understood your husband you wouldn't
feel angry at your husband it's the same
thing it's the same thing and and
feeling anxiety about next week and
feeling angry at your husband it's the
same thing okay
it's shaky water okay all right Dana
luma tangivelu Donna therefore according
to the higher muddy mica person giggle
did you have a question to look up look
I'm trying to find something unique
look up ta GS space D doesn't say I
can't say kun da dong Cheng a me look up
BTW a GS space t bt a GS space t
you got it okay we can divide this
misunderstanding of your husband into
good duck and slinky what's that mean
yeah some things you learn in this life
some wrong ideas you get taught in
school like science and yeah some wrong
ideas you were born with him okay
someone I guess you're born it would be
really nice to write a nice book about
why science is wrong because you could
improve science you could make it better
Buddhism can improve science okay kun da
da thing Guinea Lai Chi madam
so which one do you think is responsible
for the fight in the kitchen
is it the misunderstanding you were born
with or is it misunderstanding that you
learned in school you are born with it
okay you were born with the feeling that
the husband's coming from the husband
all all beings haven't even answer that
you stick the piece of grass in their
face okay question alright
not really yeah I mean the main problem
is something you were born with okay
take away milk from a baby and see what
they do you know they start yelling okay
okay alrighty Madan day long nodding
irons in Bernini now question for you
destruction view dicta can come in two
kinds what is focused on me and one is
focused on mine which one okay so now we
have two divisions of misunderstanding
number one were you born with it or did
you learn it and we decided the one
you're born with is the main cause of
trouble in the kitchen okay the one
you're born with has two versions one
holds to me one Michaels holds to
Michael and sum them how to Michael's
things okay
which one causes the most trouble yeah
the one that hosts me so here it says
minds and magic tenido that's the main
problem it's the one that holds to me
okay
I don't like this I I'm nervous about
this wing
my boss is unreasonable I was only gone
for a week and he's giving me three
weeks of work you know then you get mad
about what he's doing to me
okay and okay listen there's nard
no what does it mean word northen yeah
to hold to me okay
hold to a me but when you get good at
scripture you will hear it differently
holding to me me he's yelling at me and
it changes the meaning it's not just a
word it's not just a pronoun it's not
just me it's me I came home I did do
anything and he's yelling at me okay so
there's a that emphasis on the word is
caused by misunderstanding me okay he's
yelling at ya
and he's gonna talk about that maybe now
I think nylon eunbeom also could say now
when someone praises you Oh Stanley you
did such a good job now la dame our
lender number so then you think now my
boss is talking good you know he's
really understanding me because he
praised me you know you know not on our
shipping link board chic low books of
shopper but and when you think you know
he praised me then you get a link
low posture sharper
a very very intense me comes up in your
heart okay Stanley Stanley who did made
a still okay and Ling Bo Lopo so deep in
your heart you get this steam my boss
told me I was cool
Stanley okay that's the meaning of the
word okay I'm trying to break your pride
but I think it's just getting bigger
okay day your pain they need love doctor
some day and then you hold to that mean
okay but it's too big it's not real okay
it got bigger in your mind it got bigger
in your heart me okay if someone hurts
your friend or if someone praises your
friend you don't say candy you know if
geshe-la praises candy for helping so
many things so many projects then we
don't say and that just law says candy
you guys and you and Sydney are amazing
and then you don't say candy okay only
if they say to Michael oh you're so
smart good luck Mike
yeah okay then that's the feeling of
that faith within me
yeah that's the feeling of the
foundation mental affliction that
holding to me okay Michael got it okay
so you see it strongly when someone
praises you and criticized we're getting
to that okay Neela dot assumed a long
chopped up or char then you exceed me as
a subject subject and object they open
Allah say and then you start to get used
to this kind of attachment to me okay
Shan lot down and then you start to not
feel the same about other people okay
when they praise Michael Michael when
they praise candy yeah that's okay she
works pretty high okay it's different
isn't it it's different
okay so Dawa means you kind of get upset
at other people you don't treat them the
same
get a Penta Balladur tongue they want
people help you you start to get desire
which I like to explain as mainly not
enjoying to share with other people
everyone in this room the whole time
we're here should praise Jesus and if
they praise can be a little bit that's
not so cool I mean 100% of the time
should be aimed at NAPA chicken now
control and then when someone hurts can
I guess that's stupid guess not I made a
mistake okay then guess not get angry
okay so you can see how Parmalat mo can
you get a negative emotion towards
neutral objects what's it called in
Tibetan is called Teemo it means in the
fog dark you're in the dark okay
am I making bad karma if I look at this
carpet and I don't feel angry and I
don't feel desire am I still making
karma
yeah it's called background Karma okay
and it creates all the neutral things in
your life like I don't care if the lines
on the highway to Tucson are straight
I'm not thinking about it I don't care
but that's also created by karma okay so
mild ongoing misunderstanding of the
carpet created the neutral
lines on the highway to Tucson okay got
it
all right then he quotes numb down
what's numb down
come on of Arctica pramana but okay
doggy inanition - a dachshund challenge
in Doong Doong did I've done a young
darling the epitome did you work yeah
okay
Darian nonny this is very very profound
and I don't know me and Nancy where are
you in our hippie days the Beatles went
to India and created this great
connection with India and they came back
and they wrote this song right uh all
through the day I'm in mind I'm in mind
I'm in mind it's the song is called I
mean mine and it's criticizing this
feeling focused on busines and not candy
okay so dark your nonny
once you have guessed line then you can
have shin yeah then you're gonna have
huh candy that candy okay once you have
Kayla then you can have candy okay dark
shan't challenge and Doong Doong and
once you make that division you will
either be attached or you will hate okay
you you must make that division first
that division must come first
I am NOT you you are not me then you can
have hatred and then you can have desire
okay got it it's very beautiful it's
very beautiful
okay sinned and done did Danny young
Delhi and then in connection with this
kind of thinking yep at times a jeweler
you get all the problems of your life
all the unhappiness of your life comes
from that two more two more lines okay
then we'll take a pee-pee break
Joop align your monkey animal ooh chicks
allah tala to annoy tongue guillotine
okay all the
negative emotions all of them come from
misunderstanding me okay
Dahlia Malloy it on your chain and
someday you will see it okay then the
same books as tambomachay dollars
dollars and itching
dishing moola Chuck keep on Dumbo
now a dollar changing first step of the
process of a dirty mind is me okay
kishna okay first me okay and then you
start to prefer that the praise goes to
get okay and not the candy okay then you
start to be attached to your things okay
so the text here has a big mistake
daki which is by me but the correct the
correct reading in the tenure is GI not
G is okay it doesn't make sense with GIS
and a lot of texts have it it doesn't
make any sense without the GIS with just
GI it means mine okay so first you have
to have okay so then you have to have
candy and then you can move on to my
things you know they took my computer
she scratched my car okay got it
then you can move on to the mine
my stone okay Chucky's upon share soap
spoon last sentence okay did I say that
already I don't care
target do $100 too easy you can also do
you think what's tugging me chuggy
give me a break
that's that's a she called a shot in the
dark I'll teach you a new idiom
what's timing with gaming $100 come on
let's tug it together tugging during
that kind of target - what's the target
target under Carina tag a good joke ETV
ray hundred dollars for him okay see if
she give you okay sir the popular
abhidharma word for pleasure is not
pleasure
word can you look up the Sanskrit for me
in locusts children in in the Abbott
Dharma they don't call yomo mainly they
call it target which means subtle and
widespread I mean everywhere was close
but it's also subtle you don't know it
when you have it okay you have dinner
all day but you don't know it's subtle
and gay game is it spread to the whole
day
they should press Krishna guess I should
get the red envelope not the alligator
or the little guess not okay got it yeah
accompany your sleep
doesn't make anything but what's the
Sanskrit maybe it's direct from the
Sanskrit
Anusha
Anusha Dhanam don't know maybe Kristine
Kafka can find me the route Anusha it's
a long a or short a first one I know
means yeah that's what it is
uh no can mean atomic size it can also
mean a common prefix like afterwards
okay anyway don't worry about it all
right I mean I'm close you're close to
the toilet
don't worry Marty budget allocated
shutdown so first you have the face
which is misunderstanding your husband
and then it kind of gets focused on he's
yelling at you have to breathe okay me
you know I need anything and then he's
yelling at me if he's yelling at his
apprentice like he's yelling at his
friend if he's the only a year it's me
okay Nalla ten is chop the pentose okay
and then you get the other negative
emotions such as doubt okay doubt is
built on me somebody has to write a
graduate thesis about it it'd be
interesting you have a guest mr. Peter
come on I thought you're gonna tell us
why doubt should come from the to
emotions of liking and disliking which
have come from misunderstanding my
husband involving me
in with intention to you then you get
out that your husband loves you and
other kind of things because the
reaction was not the one you expected I
think you can say that yeah you could
say that but maybe if you're me is
really strong it's hard to admit that
maybe he came from you right it's hard
to agree you have doubt about it right
if you're me is very strong it's hard to
accept it when somebody says you you're
the problem in the kitchen okay did you
have another question because everyone
wants to p be against our promise to
people if you were really well that you
don't have to feel guilty just if you
were really well-trained you could learn
to catch those moments where the me is
very strong at that point practically
what could you do with that I think you
have to take it to some situation and
some person okay you have to apply it to
something but in the moment when you're
like I think you could meditate on it
and try to isolate the feeling of me and
maybe you could think of some candy and
compare how strong is your candy to your
meal okay that's a good mentor huh how
does an aria view it differently two
kinds of arias okay I just have two
periods in their life number one when
they remember what they saw number two
when they forgot what they saw okay so
are you can have desire aya can have
anger they are not our hunt they didn't
reach nirvana so the only pom-pom assume
they only remove three negativities what
are they for a fast toilet trip doubt
about the power believes that it's cool
to jump on our spear and reach the
and yeah intellectually believe that the
husband is coming from himself
they can have a deep emotional belief
that's okay they can still be aria but
if you ask them come on it's the husband
really coming from himself they'll say
you know yeah now I remember
okay okay alright last sentence they'll
attend a less son and due to that do to
your monks you begin to collect new
seeds you begin to collect karma and due
to the Karma you live in the wheel of
pain you live in the real pain so
there's a seven-step of my trailer we
studied it a bunch of times
it's the flowchart for Santa okay and
you should learn it maybe word can teach
it next in Mexico okay it comes from my
trailer it comes from guitarra Tantra
what's it do you llama get llama okay it
comes from my trance okay and it's a
beautiful flowchart and so you have to
learn it he kind of put it here but it's
not as clear okay
all right you earned a special vacation